UNITE HERE Operations Department Files 6200/003
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE Operations Department Files
1989-2001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE
6200/003
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Records.
6299073
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, March 03, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
UNITE HERE is a labor union in the United States and Canada, that was formed in 2004 by the merger of the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE) and Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE). The membership is made up mainly of workers in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries. In 2005, UNITE HERE left the AFL-CIO and joined the Change to Win Federation along with other unions including the Teamsters, SEIU and the UFCW. In may 2009, Bruce Raynor, president, left UNITE HERE, taking with hiim several local unions and between 105,000 and 150,000 members. They formed Workers United. September 17, 2009, UNITE HERE announced that it would re-join the AFL-CIO.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6200: UNITE HERE Records
Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States; Textile workers--Labor unions--United States.; Collective bargaining--Textile industry-- United States.; Collective bargaining--Clothing industry--United States.; UNITE HERE (Organization); Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Textile Workers Union of America; UNITE HERE (Organization) Operations Dept.
6299073
- 75 / 50 Celebrating Our Heritage. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Logo. (English and French)
- ACTWU. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Steward's Pin. Artwork.
- Coalition of Labor Women. Health Care. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Convention., 1989-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Delegate's Guides.
- Convention. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Logo.
- Convention., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Mission Statement.
- Delgado, Ernesto Jofre., 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Great Liberal UI Scam. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  English and French. La Grande Escroquerie de l'Assurance-Emploi de Liberaux.
- Haiti After the Coup: Sweatshop or Real Development? (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Flyer.
- Made in GAP Sweatshop. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Means of Production., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Metro New York Labor Communications Council (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Metro New York Labor Press Council, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National Council of Negro Women. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Ad Hoc Labor Committee.
- Sidney Hillman Foundation. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Spinning Yarns and Shirt Tales. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Standing Together. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Call to Justice. Que se Haga Justica. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Stickers. (English and Spanish).
- Organize! Mobilize! UNITE! (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Stickers.
- Union Logo. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- UNITE!. Business Cards. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Mort, Jo-Ann Rayner, Bruce Romney, Edgar
- We're With Atlanta. UNITE! (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Students Against Sweatshops. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Use Your Voice... Vote! Use Su Palabra... Vote!, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  English and Spanish.
- Wheat for Senate. (Box 1, Folder 25)